A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Room 5600, Rockefeller family office, Series 2 FA455
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Room 5600, Rockefeller family office, Series 2
1920-1979
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
Rockefeller, Mary (Mary Todhunter Clark)
Rockefeller, Margaretta Fitler
FA455
32.73 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate.
Related Archival Materials note
Additional images of Nelson A. Rockefeller and or his interests will be found in the following:
Rockefeller Family Photographs. Most of the photos of Nelson A. Rockefeller in his childhood and many photos of Nelson A. Rockefeller as an adult with his parents can be found in 1005 John D. Rockefeller Jr. Family - Children's Albums or Group Portraits. See also John D. Rockefeller Jr. - Business - 17 West 54th Street.
International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC) Archives.
Nelson A. Rockefeller papers, Art, Series C (FA340). This series documents the management of Nelson A. Rockefeller's art collection and includes photos of a portion of the works of art he owned.
Arrangement note
The Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs are arranged in the following series:
Series 1008: Nelson A. Rockefeller family. Series 2: Room 5600, Rockefeller family office. Series 3: Gubernatorial Press Office. Series 4: Gubernatorial Press Office. Series 5: Gubernatorial, Robert A. (Bob) Wands. Series 6: Vice Presidential. Series 7: Unprocessed photographs.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series:
Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
Other Finding Aids
For other Nelson A. Rockefeller photographic holdings, please see the following finding aids:
FA454 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Nelson A. Rockefeller family, Series 1008
FA456 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Gubernatorial Press Office, Series 3
FA457 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Gubernatorial Press Office, Series 4
FA458 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Gubernatorial, Robert A. (Bob) Wands, Series 5
FA459 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Vice Presidential, Series 6
FA460 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Unprocessed photographs, Series 7
Other Finding Aids note
For other Rockefeller family photographic holdings, please see the following finding aids:
FA445 Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001
FA446 William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002
FA447 John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003
FA448 William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004
FA449 John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005
FA450 Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006
FA451 John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007
FA452 Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009
FA453 David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010
For related materials, please see the following finding aids:
FA340 Nelson A. Rockefeller papers, Art, Series C
FA084 International Basic Economy Corporation records
Scope and Contents
This series of photographs, originating from the Rockefeller family office (Room 5600), comprehensively documents Nelson A. Rockefeller's life and career including his personal, professional and political activities. Family and personal photographs include invidividual formal and informal portraits, group portraits and events, as well as Rockefeller family homes, a selection of images of his art collection, and travel prints. There is a large selection of images of dignitaries and friends, as well as photographic documentation of Nelson Rockefeller's business activities, philanthropic activities, and government service. The series also includes a wide variety of images of gubernatorial appearances and campaign activities as well as photographs pertaining to Nelson's service as Vice President of the United States.
Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Arts; Art, Modern; Rockefeller family -- Art collections; Political campaigns -- United States; New York (State); New York (N.Y.); State governments -- United States; Photographs
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Photographs, Room 5600, Rockefeller family office, 1920-1979; 2; 32.73 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents note
  KEY: Numbers in brackets indicate the following:
  ( ) number of unique images in the file
  [ ] photos described in earlier list (c. 1960). See Appendix A.
  { } individual photo number.
  Arrangement
  For ease of access, the material is arranged into subseries by:
  Photographs (Boxes 1-38, including Box 2A). Overized (Boxes O 1, O 2, O 3, O 4, O 5, O 6, O 7, O 8, O 9, O 10, O 11, O 12).
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Photographs, 1909-1979; 18.33 Cubic Feet 39 legal document boxes.
    - Art
      - Photographs of objects in Seal Harbor (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Mostly photos of art works owned by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., undated; (147) (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Mostly photos of art works owned by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Museum of Modern Art - Opening of Robert Motherwell show, 1965 September; (3) (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Museum of Modern Art - Collection Exhibition, 1969 May; (14) (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - NAR Art Collections (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Study for UN Building Sculpture (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - NAR Art Collections - Museum of Primitive Art, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Associates
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - Berent Freile, undated
        - Sernando E. Delgado, 1958
        - Henry Kissinger, 1975
        - Francis A. Jamieson and Wallace K. Harrison, circa 1945
      - Associates (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - Ted Braun, undated
        - Megan Marshack, undated
        - William Ronan, undated
        - Richard Parson, undated
        - F. Reid, undated
    - Businesses
      - Hotel Avila (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Wallace Harrison and others in front of the Hotel Avila, 1944; (2) (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC)
        - Nelson A. Rockefeller Visit to Caracas, Venezuela (Automercado), 1954; (5) (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller Farms, Venezuela
        - NAR Farms, Inc. - Monte Sacro, (16) (Box 2, Folder 13)
        - Hacienda Monte Sacro - Duplicates for Distribution, (50) (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - Hacienda Monte Sacro - Duplicates for Distribution (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - Hacienda Monte Sacro - Duplicates for Distribution (Box 2, Folder 16)
        - Hacienda Monte Sacro - Duplicates for Distribution (Box 2A, Folder 17)
        - Hacienda Monte Sacro - Duplicates for Distribution (Box 2A, Folder 18)
        - Hacienda Monte Sacro (Box 2A, Folder 19)
        - Hacienda Monte Sacro (Box 2A, Folder 20)
        - Hacienda Monte Sacro (Box 2A, Folder 21)
        - Hacienda Monte Sacro (Box 2A, Folder 22)
        - Hacienda Monte Sacro (Box 2A, Folder 23)
        - Nelson A. Rockefeller Travel- Monte Sacro Trip, 1954; (43) (Box 3, Folder 24)
        - Nelson A. Rockefeller Trip to Monte Sacro, 1954; (14 photos, 106 images on contact sheets) (Box 3, Folder 25)
        - Nelson A. Rockefeller at Monte Sacro, 1958; (1) (Box 3, Folder 26)
        - Monte Sacro, 1960 April; (5) (Box 3, Folder 27)
        - Monete Sacro, 1960 August; (19) (Box 3, Folder 28)
        - Venezuela, General, circa 1959; (37) (Box 3, Folder 29)
        - NAR Farms Miscellaneous, (149) (Box 3, Folder 30)
        - PACA's Chirgua State Farm, Carabo State, 1949 June; (4) (Box 3, Folder 31)
        - Palo Gordo - Rice Growing, 1958 August (Box 3, Folder 32)
        - Palo Gordo Farm, 1960 June; (6) (Box 4, Folder 33)
        - Palo Gordo Farm, 1960 December; (15) (Box 4, Folder 34)
        - Improvements, undated; (22) (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Rockefeller Center, Inc. (Box 4)
        - Nelson A. Rockefeller at Rockefeller Center, General, 1935-1952; (24) (Box 4, Folder 36)
        - Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, J., Col. Arthur Woods, Rinaldo Stroppe-Quaglia, Antonio Mosconi, 1933; (7) (Box 4, Folder 37)
        - Ground Breaking for New Time & Life Building, 1958; (4) (Box 4, Folder 38)
        - Returning Servicemen to Rockefeller Center, 1946; (1) (Box 4, Folder 39)
        - United Nations Flag Raising Ceremony, 1956; (3) (Box 4, Folder 40)
        - Nelson A. Rockefeller Awarding Rockefeller Center Scholarship Awards, 1956 June 6; (1) (Box 4, Folder 41)
        - Rockefeller Center Under Construction, 1932; (1) (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Colleges and Universities
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller at Colleges and Universities, General, 1950-1977 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller at Michigan State College Commencement, 1951 June 3; (7) (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller at Spelman College, 1954 September; (3) (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller looking at portrait of his mother, Spelman College, 1957 April 1; (1) (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller with Dignitaries and U.S. Presidents
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President and Mrs. Roosevelt, 1942; (3) (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President Truman, 1950; (2) (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President Eisenhower, 1954-1955; (2) (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President Kennedy, 1961; (6); (2 photos, 1 contact sheet) (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President Johnson, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President Nixon, 1960 September 28 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President Nixon, 1972 October 20 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President Nixon, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President Ford, 1974; (2) (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller with Dignitaries - Latin America
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller in Brazil, including with President Vargas, 1942; (4) [24] (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller greets former President of Paraguay, Higinio Moringio, 1945; (1) [33] (Box 5, Folder 57)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller in Carroya del Rio, circa 1943; (1) [29] (Box 5, Folder 58)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller - Colombia - Alberto Lleras Comargo, 1945; 3 (Box 5, Folder 58A)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller; Joao Napoleao de Andrade, president of the Brazilian agricultural agency ACAR, 1956; (1) [35] (Box 5, Folder 59)
      - President Kubitschek greets Nelson A. Rockefeller at the presidential palace, Rio, 1958; (1) [49] (Box 5, Folder 60)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller conducts a press conference in Rio de Janeiro, 1942; (2) [21] (Box 5, Folder 61)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller; Berent Friele; Brazilian Foreign Minister Aranha, Rio de Janeiro, 1958; (3) [10] (Box 5, Folder 62)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller visits President Picado, Costa Rica, 1944; (1) [18] (Box 5, Folder 63)
      - Berent Friele; Eduardo Mendoza, Venezuelan Minister of Agriculture; Nelson A. Rockefeller; Juan Pablo Perez Alfonso, Minister of Development, Caracas, 1947; (1) [19] (Box 5, Folder 64)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller at a meeting, Morelos, Mexico, 1942; (1) [25] (Box 5, Folder 65)
      - Mexican President Manuel Avila Camacho; Ezequiel Padilla; Nelson A. Rockefeller in Morelos, Mexico, 1943; (2) [69] (Box 5, Folder 66)
        - Dr. Felipe A. Espil, Argentine Ambassador to the U.S.; Nelson A. Rockefeller, Buenos Aires, 1942; (1)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with Herbert Moses, president of the Brazilian Press Association, 1958; (1) [54] (Box 5, Folder 67)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller; Jose Irineu Cabral, executive director of ABCAR; Joao Napoleao de Andrade, President of ABCAR; Walter Crawford, 1958; (1) [58] (Box 5, Folder 68)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President Elie Lescot of Haiti, 1944 November; (1) [60] (Box 5, Folder 69)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller calls on President Juan Antonio Rios of Chile, 1942; (1) [62] (Box 5, Folder 70)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller calls on President Tiburcio Carias of Honduras, Tegucigalpa, 1944; (1) [63] (Box 5, Folder 71)
      - Dr. Alfredo Solf y Muro, banquet in honor of Nelson A. Rockefeller, Lima, 1942; (25) [64] (Box 5, Folder 72)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller addresses a meeting of Peruvian government officials, Lima, 1942; (1) [65] (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with Mrs. Juscelino Kubitschek, wife of the president of Brazil, 1958; (3) [52] (Box 5, Folder 74)
      - Monsignor Fernando Cento, Papal Nuncio to Peru; Nelson A. Rockefeller; Julio East, Peruvian Minister of Finance and Commerce; Manuel Gallagher, Foreign Minister, 1942; (1) [66] (Box 5, Folder 75)
      - Dr. Ricardo Crespo Cerdonez, Ecuadorian Minister of Agriculture; Nelson A. Rockefeller; Boaz Long, US Ambassador to Ecuador, Quito, 1942; (1) [67] (Box 5, Folder 76)
      - Felipe A. Espil, Argentine Ambassador to the United States, welcomes Nelson A. Rockefeller to Buenos Aires, 1942; [71] (Box 5, Folder 77)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller; President Isaias Medina of Venezuela; Secretary of State Stettinius; General George Marshall, Washington, DC, 1945; (2) [72] (Box 5, Folder 78)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller; Brazilian General Pedro Aurelio de Gois Monteiro; Eurico Gaspar Dutra, Minister of War, 1942; (1) [78] (Box 5, Folder 79)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, President Meplina, Washington, 1945; (1) [186] (Box 5, Folder 80)
      - Luthero Vargos (son of President Getulio Vargos, Brazil), circa 1950; (1) (Box 5, Folder 81)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller; Mayor Wagner's luncheon for President Kubischek, 1956 January; (1) (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with Argentine Journalists, Washington DC, 1943 April; (1) (Box 5, Folder 83)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with President Jose Maria Velasco Ibarra of Ecuador, (2) (Box 5, Folder 84)
      - Galo Plaza, 1958-1970 (Box 5, Folder 85)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller with Luis Munoz-Marin, Governor of Puerto Rico, and Eleanor Roosevelt, 1960; (3) (Box 5, Folder 86)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, President and Mrs. Contreras, Venezuela, 1939 March; (2) (Box 5, Folder 87)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, President Dutra, Cardinal Spelman, Pan American Society Dinner, Waldorf Astoria, 1949 May; (4) [112] (Box 5, Folder 88)
      - Romulo Betancourt, then president of Venezuela, Nelson A. Rockefeller at Monte Sacro, 1963; (10) [37] (Box 5, Folder 89)
      - Miscellaneous, 1939-1949; (5) (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller with Dignitaries- Miscellaneous
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Golda Meir, Louis Lefkowitz, 1958 October 18; 1 contact sheet, 4 photos. (Box 5, Folder 91)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Queen Beatrice, (12) (Box 5, Folder 92)
      - Visit of King and Queen of Denmark to Albany, 1960 October 6; (24) (Box 5, Folder 93)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Charles de Gaulle, Waldorf-Astoria, 1960 April 26; (1) (Box 5, Folder 94)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, President Segni of Italy, Waldorf-Astoria, 1964 January 17; (1) (Box 5, Folder 95)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Prince Bertil of Sweden, circa 1975; (1) (Box 5, Folder 96)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mrs. Nelson A. Rockefeller, Ambassador Gaja of Italy, 1976 July; (16) (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family -Group Portraits
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family Portrait, 1958; 3 contact sheets, 9 photos (Box 6, Folder 98)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family Grouping, 1958; (4) (Box 6, Folder 99)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mrs. Nelson A. Rockefeller, grandchildren, 1958; (4) (Box 6, Folder 100)
      - Return of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s body from Arizona, circa 1960; (9) (Box 6, Folder 101)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Ann, Mary, 1959 August 21; (1) (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family - Brothers
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller and brothers, circa 1935-1940; (2) (Box 7, Folder 103)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller 3rd at Hawes House, circa 1940; (2) (Box 7, Folder 104)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller and his brother David visit Brazil, 1948; (1) (Box 7, Folder 105)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller and brother Winthrop Rockefeller, 1968; (5) (Box 7, Folder 106)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Brothers, Colonial Williamsburg, Abby Rockefeller Folk Art Collection Opening, (1) (Box 7, Folder 107)
      - "CBS Reports" Photos- Nelson A. Rockefeller and Brothers and Sister Abby, 1973; (8) (Box 7, Folder 108)
      - Brotherhood in Action Dinner, Nelson A. Rockefeller and Winthrop Rockefeller, 1967 May 10; (3) (Box 7, Folder 109)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, LSR, Swearing in Commissioner of Parks and Recreation, 1970 July 24 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family - Mary Todhunter Clark Rockefeller - Portraits
      - Portraits by Eder, 1960; (7) (Box 7, Folder 111)
      - Gubernatorial, with reporters at Executive Mansion, circa 1959; (4) (Box 7, Folder 112)
      - On boat, (2) (Box 7, Folder 113)
      - Portraits, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 113A)
      - Portraits, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 113B)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family - Mary Todhunter Clark Rockefeller - Wedding
      - Wedding pictures, Bachrach, 1930; (9) (Box 7, Folder 114)
      - Mary Todhunter Clark with Nelson A. Rockefeller, Honeymoon, (5) (Box 7, Folder 115)
      - Mary Todhunter Clark with Nelson A. Rockefeller before wedding, (6) (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family - Mary C. Rockefeller - with Nelson A. Rockefeller and Children
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mary C. Rockefeller, on farm in Venezuela, 1958 November; (13) (Box 7, Folder 117)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mrs. Nelson A. Rockefeller, Portraits of couple in Albany Mansion, 1958; (9) (Box 7, Folder 118)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mary C. Rockefeller with Richard Aldrich Family, circa 1960; (3) (Box 7, Folder 119)
      - Mary C. Rockefeller - miscellaneous, 3 photos, 1 negative, 6 slides (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family - Margaretta M. Rockefeller (Happy) (MFR) - Portraits
      - M.F. Rockefeller, Portrait, circa 1967; (1) (Box 8, Folder 121)
      - MFR, 1963; (1) (Box 8, Folder 122)
      - MFR Portrait, circa 1964; (1) (Box 8, Folder 123)
      - MFR Portrait, circa 1965; (1) (Box 8, Folder 124)
      - MFR Portrait - Miscellaneous, 1956-circa 1985; (8) (Box 8, Folder 125)
      - MFR, 1968 June; (3) (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - MFR Portrait, circa 1973; (2) (Box 8, Folder 127)
      - MFR, 1997 December (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family - Margaretta M. Rockefeller (Happy) (MFR) - Wedding
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, MFR wedding, 1963 May; (7 contact sheets with 88 images, 72 negative images, 7 photos) (Box 9, Folder 129)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, MFR on Honeymoon at Monte Sacro, Venezuela, 1963; (2) (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family - Margaretta M. Rockefeller (Happy) (MFR), with Nelson A. Rockefeller and Children
      - MFR with Nelson A. Rockefeller, Jr., circa 1965; (1) (Box 9, Folder 131)
      - MFR, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller Jr, John F. Kennedy Airport, 1966 June 26 (Box 9, Folder 132)
      - Mrs. Nelson A. Rockefeller with Children in Hawaii, 1968; (1 contact sheet with 30 images) (Box 9, Folder 133)
      - MFR at Colonial Williamsburg, 1970; (4) (Box 9, Folder 134)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller and Margaretta F. Rockefeller, Skiing, undated; (7) (Box 9, Folder 135)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller and Margaretta F. Rockefeller, Miscellaneous, (10) (Box 9, Folder 136)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family - Children
      - Rodman C. Rockefeller, 1 photo, 4 contact sheets (Box 9, Folder 137)
      - Rodman C. Rockefeller, 1954-1966; (19) (Box 9, Folder 138)
      - Rodman C. Rockefeller, Bernardo O' Higgins, Order of Merit, 1964 March 18; (6) (Box 9, Folder 139)
      - Rodman C. Rockefeller, official photo, NY Times Studios, 1964 September; (9) (Box 9, Folder 140)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Steven C. Rockefeller, Wedding Pictures and Portraits of Mrs. Steven Rockefeller, 1959; (2) (Box 9, Folder 141)
      - Anne-Marie (Mrs. Steven C. Rockefeller), 1957, 1959, 1967; (5) (Box 9, Folder 142)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Steven C. Rockefeller, 1968; (1) (Box 9, Folder 143)
      - Mrs. Steven C. Rockefeller (Anne Marie Rasmussen), 1968; (1) (Box 9, Folder 144)
      - Ann Clark Rockefeller (Mrs. Robert L. Pierson), 1952; (2) (Box 9, Folder 145)
      - Ann Clark Rockefeller (Mrs. Robert L. Pierson), Wedding Portraits/Proofs, (11) (Box 9, Folder 146)
      - Mary Clark Rockefeller (Mrs. William J. Strawbridge, Jr.), Portrait, (1) (Box 9, Folder 147)
      - Mary Clark Rockefeller (Mrs. William J. Strawbridge, Jr.), Wedding Portrait, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 148)
      - Ann, Steven, Rodman, Mary and Michael - childhood photos, (10) (Box 10, Folder 149)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Jr. and Mark F. Rockefeller, Childhood Photos, (52 photos, 3 contact sheets with 17 images, 11 negative images, 32 microjacket images) (Box 10, Folder 150)
      - Mary Rockefeller Debut, 1956 June; (36 strips of negatives) (Box 10, Folder 151)
      - Rockefeller Family Christmas Parties, 1948-1968; (68) (Box 10, Folder 152)
      - Rockefeller Family Christmas Party, Playhouse, 1973; (18) (Box 10, Folder 153)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family - Winthrop Paul Rockefeller, Jr.'s Christening, 1976 August; (5) (Box 10, Folder 154)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family - John D. Rockefeller, Sr., (1) (Box 10, Folder 155)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller - Government Service, Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller Photographs - Coordinator's Office, 1940-1944; (45) (Box 11, Folder 156)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Washington, General Kirk (Surgeon General) General Dunham, 1945; (4) (Box 11, Folder 157)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller - Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs, Wartime Trips to Latin America, circa 1942-1944; (3) (Box 11, Folder 158)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller visits Central America, 1944 Spring; (14) (Box 11, Folder 159)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1942; (2) (Box 11, Folder 160)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller - Government Service- Assistant Secretary of State for American Republic Affairs
      - Inter-American Conference on Problems of War and Peace, 1945 February; (11) (Box 11, Folder 161)
      - United Conference on International Organization, San Francisco, 1945; (9) (Box 11, Folder 162)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller - Government Service, Inter-American Development Commission
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller - Tarrytown Lunch for IADC Conference, 1944 May; (3) (Box 11, Folder 163)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Francisco Tudela, Inter-American Development Commission at Lima, 1942 Avara Warren IAC, [74] (Box 11, Folder 164)
      - Nelson A. Rockefeller Political - Inter-American Development Commission, 1942-1944; (2) (Box 11, Folder 165)